Barry Peavy

Web & Graphic Designer / Product & UI/UX Designer / Front-End Developer



barry.peavy@gmail.com



+1 678 524 7640



barrypeavy.com



linkedin.com/in/barrypeavy



portfolio

Technical Skills

- HTML/CSS, Responsive Design
- Bootstrap, Tailwind
- Figma, Adobe XD, InVision
- Illustrator, Sketch, Photoshop
- Wordpress, Wix, Misc CMS
- Visual Studio Code, Sublime
- MS Office, Google Docs
- JIRA, Pivotal Tracker, Azure DevOps
- Emails, MailChimp, Litmus
- GitHub, Rails env, Slack, Docker
- Basic WCAG/ARIA/508 Accessibility

Professional Summary

I am a hybrid web/graphic designer and front-end developer with 15+ years remote experience, well-versed in both creative work (Adobe Creative Suite, Figma) — and more technical work in HTML/CSS and frameworks such as Bootstrap and Tailwind.

Outside of work, my hobbies and interests include playing guitar and banjo, singing, background/commercial acting, nationwide hiking/camping/overlanding, golf, fitness, and DIY projects. I also travel frequently to visit my daughter in Texas, and family on the Georgia coast.

Employment

Web Designer — Front-End Developer (contractor)

TruChoiceFinancial.com



□ Apr 2023 — Present

CSS / HTML / Bootstrap / Front-End Developer / Graphic Designer. Responsible for designing, coding, testing, and maintaining the public-facing website, as well as the logged in client portal. Also perform email design/code and marketing graphics.

Web Designer - Front-End Developer

FlexJobs / BOLD



□ Jan 2014 — Present

For 10 years with FlexJobs, I have performed web design (Adobe CS, Figma, Sketch) and extensive front-end markup (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap) for the entire website, in an Agile dev environment (using Visual Studio, Jira, Rails, Github, Slack).

In this role I work closely with everyone from the CEO, to Project and Product managers, Dev Directors, and Back-End Engineers. I also perform device testing for responsiveness. FlexJobs was acquired by BOLD in early 2023.

Interactive Web Designer

Definition6

Atlanta GA

⊕ Mar 2007 — Dec 2007

Took design comps, wireframes, charter documents, and UI layouts and translated into website builds, using semantic HTML and CSS. Performed graphic design work and web page/application design, as well as extensive cross-browser testing. Participated in site-planning and estimate meetings and interacted with various teams.

Web Designer — HTML/CSS Developer

Various Contract Roles

Atlanta GA

(E) Jun 2004 — Dec 2013

Worked on a variety of web/graphic design and development projects for numerous companies — including <u>AutoTrader.com</u>, <u>VeriSign</u>, BellSouth, <u>Dodge Communications</u>, <u>Jackson Healthcare</u>, and <u>Xceleration</u>. These contracts were worked via several IT placement firms — The Creative Group, Matrix Resources, etc.

Studies Abroad Grad Classes

Georgia Southern University

University of Georgia Cortona, Italy

Statesboro Georgia

Education

BFA — Printmaking

Webmaster

Coweta County Schools

Newnan GA

□ Apr 2003 — May 2004

Planned, designed, developed, and tested the main CCSS website. Performed all graphic design work, and built all database-driven web pages and applications.

Developed and managed style specifications for the CCSS website. Tested for cross-browser/OS compatibility and Section 508 standards compliance.

Responsible for the CCSS Employee Intranet, as well as management of 30 individual school websites maintained by school-based technology specialists. Served as the help desk web design resource for these specialists.